nsu.edu 2006-06-21

# 61.001: Internet Website Acceptable Use and Privacy Policy

                                61.001: Internet Website Acceptable Use and Privacy Policy
 Responsible Executive:        Vice President for Research and Technology
     Responsible Office:       Enterprise Information Systems
           Related Policy:
    Approved-On Date:          January 11, 2006
           Effective Date:     September 17, 2003
           Revision Date:      November 11, 2005
Policy Statement
         The following information explains the NSU Website Disclaimer, Internet Privacy
Policy, Copyright & Correspondence Policy as well as Terms of Agreement - which Norfolk
State University has adopted for its website (web pages at addresses beginning with
“http://www.nsu.edu”).
         Your access to the Website is in consideration of your agreement with these Terms and
Conditions of Use. By accessing, browsing, and utilizing this website, you accept, without
limitation or qualification, these Terms and Conditions of Use. We reserve the right to amend
this policy at any time without notice.
Purpose
         This policy sets forth terms and conditions of use of the Norfolk State University (NSU)
website. Your access to and use of the NSU website is subject to the following terms and
conditions, as well as applicable state and federal laws.
Authority
         We protect our records in accordance with our obligations as defined by applicable
Virginia statutes, including, but not limited to, the “Virginia Privacy Protection Act of 1976”, the
“Virginia Freedom of Information Act”, and by any applicable U.S. federal laws. Any attempt
to use any information, feature, or other aspect of the site to engage in criminal conduct will be
vigorously prosecuted. Any unlawful actions may be subject to criminal prosecution under the
Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986, and other criminal laws, and may also result in civil
liability.
Disclaimer:
         The contents of the Norfolk State University (NSU) website are provided as general
information only. NSU makes no warranty, either expressed or implied regarding the
completeness, accuracy, or currency of either this information or its suitability for any practical
purpose.
61.001: Internet Website Acceptable Use and Privacy Policy                                         1

         This site also contains hypertext links to websites created, and controlled by other
organizations. These links are provided for your convenience only and are not intended as an
endorsement by NSU of the organizations operating these sites or as a warranty of the
information they contain.
         By accessing the information on this website, you agree that Norfolk State University
shall not be liable to you for any loss or injury caused in procuring, compiling, or delivering the
information. In no event will NSU, or the contributors of information to this site, be liable to you
or anyone else for any action taken by you in reliance on such information or for any
consequential, special or similar damages.
         Furthermore, the inclusion of links to particular items in hypertext are not intended to
reflect their importance, nor is it intended to endorse any views expressed or products or service
offered via these links, or the organizations sponsoring the corresponding sites.
         Norfolk State University may make improvements and/or changes to its features,
functionality, or content at any time.
Privacy Notice
         Norfolk State University provides this Internet site as a public service. We do not obtain
personally identifying information about you when you visit this site unless you choose to
provide such information to us.
         Any information collected within the context of your email inquiry or comment is used
only for the expressed purpose of responding to your inquiry or comment. We collect personally
identifiable information only if specifically and knowingly provided by you.
         For site management, information is collected for statistical purposes. NSU’s computer
system uses software programs to create summary statistics, which are used for purposes such as
assessing what information is of most and least interest, determining technical design
specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas. This information is not
expressed in any form that would reveal personally identifiable information.
         NSU provides numerous online applications, forms and queries. When a user visits the
NSU website to perform a transaction (sending an application, initiating a query, receiving a
query response, etc), the web server receives data or sends a response and then may send a
cookie prior to breaking the connection with the user.
    A cookie is a small piece of software that is placed by a web server on users’ personal
computers and is then used to personalize the site when a visitor returns. A transaction or
session, may involve a number of such information exchanges, each followed by a break in the
connection. In order to maintain the state (where one is in the process) of a transaction, the NSU
websites may place session cookies in memory allocated to users’ browsers. Session cookies
permit the users to perform transactions as if they were connected to the NSU website
throughout the course of the transactions or sessions. Session cookies are erased from the users’
61.001: Internet Website Acceptable Use and Privacy Policy                                         1

systems when they close their browsers; other cookies have an expiration date, or can be cleared
from the users’ cache. We will not use cookies to: acquire information about you, relay your
name to third-party mailing lists, scrutinize your web usage for marketing purposes by third
parties, or penetrate your hard drive.
      I.     Choice to provide information
             There is no legal requirement for you to provide any information at our website.
             However, some services of the website may not be fully functional without providing
             requested information. Failure of your browser to accept cookies will not prevent
             your use of our website, but may prevent certain features from working. If you wish
             to not provide this optional information, a particular feature or service associated with
             that part of the web page will not be available to you.
      II.    Information we collect
             When you access our website the routing or client information and the technical
             information listed below, is automatically collected. No other information is
             collected through our website except when you deliberately decide to send it to us
             (for example, by clicking on a link to send us an email). All information collected by
             the website consists of the following:
             1. Routing or client information: the Internet domain and Internet address of the
                  computer you are using.
             2. Essential technical information: identification of the page or service you are
                  requesting, type of browser and operating system you are using, and the date and
                  time of access.
             3. Nonessential technical information: the Internet address of the website from
                  which you linked directly to our website, and the "cookie information" described
                  below in number 5.
             4. Optional information: when you send us an e-mail- your name, e-mail address,
                  and the content of your e-mail; when you fill out online forms- all the data you
                  choose to fill in or confirm.
             5. Cookies: Our website places a “cookie" on your computer, unless your browser is
                  set to reject cookies. The cookie enables our website to recognize that you have
                  visited our website before and does not contain any personal information.
      III. How the collected information is used
             Routing information is used to route the requested web page to your computer for
             viewing. We send the requested web page and the routing information to our Internet
             service provider or other entities involved in transmitting the requested page to you.
61.001: Internet Website Acceptable Use and Privacy Policy                                           2

             We do not control the privacy practices of those entities. Essential and nonessential
             technical information helps us respond to your request in an appropriate format and
             helps us plan website improvements.
             Optional information enables us to provide services or information tailored more
             specifically to your needs or to forward your message or inquiry to another entity that
             is better able to do so, and also it allows us to plan website improvements.
             We may keep your information indefinitely, but we ordinarily delete the transaction
             routing information from our computer within 30 days after the web page is
             transmitted and do not try to obtain any information to link it to the individuals who
             browse our website. However, on rare occasions when a "hacker" attempts to breach
             computer security, logs of routing information are retained to permit a security
             investigation and in such cases may be forwarded together with any other relevant
             information in our possession to law enforcement agencies. We use this transaction
             routing information primarily in a statistical summary type format to assess site
             content and server performance. We may share this summary information with our
             business partners when needed.
             Optional information is retained in accordance with the records retention schedules at
             the Library of Virginia.
             Under the “Virginia Freedom of Information Act”, any records in our possession at
             the time of a “Freedom of Information Request” might be subject to being inspected
             by, or disclosed to, members of the public.                   However, all identifiable
             confidential/personal information will be removed prior to releasing the routing
             information.
Copyrights
         Copyright of the materials contained in this website is owned by Norfolk State
University. These materials may be used, downloaded, reproduced, publicly displayed or
reprinted for personal or non-commercial purposes provided that the following attribution
appears in all copies: "Reproduced with permission of Norfolk State University, Norfolk, VA.
Permission to reproduce materials for commercial application (e.g., news article) must be
obtained in writing. The materials contained in this website may not be modified in any way.
         The site may also offer multimedia for viewing, graphic images, data, and other
materials.       Some materials may be licensed from outside sources.                Please contact
webmaster@nsu.edu for image license information. All rights to these materials are reserved to
Norfolk State University and/or the copyright owners who license such materials to us. Where
indicated, prior permission to use, download, reproduce, publicly display or reprint any of these
materials must be obtained from NSU or other copyright owner.
61.001: Internet Website Acceptable Use and Privacy Policy                                         3

         The name Norfolk State University (NSU) and its trademarks, symbols and logos are
trademarked and owned by NSU and should not be used without the prior expressed written
permission of NSU.
         Note that Norfolk State University has no control over personal pages or off-campus web
and gopher sites linked to this official server, and NSU is not responsible for their accuracy or
content. Norfolk State University is responsible only for those pages created for the official web
site.
Web Security Guidelines
         The key objective of the web security guidelines is to protect the data integrity of the
Norfolk State University website. These guidelines are written to make it clear that users are
responsible for understanding and respecting the security rules of the site.
         In case of a violation of the website security guidelines, investigations will be performed
to determine how and why the violation has occurred. The appropriate corrective action will be
taken.
      I.     Internal Users
             1. Users that are given permission to modify files using the Content Management
                  System (CMS) are not permitted to modify files that are not their own, even if
                  they have write permissions. Users of the CMS only have permission to modify
                  their files and are never to modify CMS system settings or configurations.
             2. Copying of copyrighted software is not permitted. Any copyrighted or licensed
                  software supplied to you may not be duplicated unless explicitly stated that you
                  may do so Contact webmaster@nsu.edu for copyright/license status of software.
             3. Users sitting on the Norfolk State University local area network (LAN) in no
                  circumstances are permitted to violate a remote website’s security policy. Any
                  unlawful or unethical interaction with outside organizations from the Norfolk
                  State University LAN is intolerable.
      II.    External Users
             1. Norfolk State University will not tolerate users, on or off the local area network,
                  to hack the services of the Norfolk State University website for research purposes.
                  Norfolk State University does not permit this type of research.
      III. Overall Conduct
             You agree to access and use this website only for lawful purposes. You are solely
             responsible for the knowledge and adherence to any and all laws, statutes, rules and
61.001: Internet Website Acceptable Use and Privacy Policy                                          4

             regulations pertaining to your use of this website. By accessing this site, you agree
             that you will NOT:
              1. Use the site to commit a criminal offense or to encourage others to conduct that
                  which would constitute a criminal offense or give rise to a civil liability.
              2. Post or transmit any unlawful, threatening, libelous, harassing, defamatory,
                  vulgar, obscene, pornographic, profane, or otherwise objectionable content.
              3. Use this website to impersonate other parties or entities.
              4. Use this website to upload any content that contains a software virus, computer
                  code, files, or programs that may alter, damage, or interrupt the functionality of
                  the Website or the hardware or software of any person who accesses the website.
              5. Upload, post, e-mail, or otherwise transmit any materials that you do not have a
                  right to transmit under any law or under a contractual relationship.
              6. Alter, damage, or delete any content posted on the website.
              7. Disrupt the normal flow of communication in any way.
              8. Claim a relationship with or speak for any business, association, or other
                  organization for which you are not authorized to claim such a relationship.
              9. Post or transmit any unsolicited advertising, promotional materials, or other
                  forms of solicitation.
              10. Post any material that infringes or violates the intellectual property rights of
                  another, or collect or store personal information about others.
    IV.      Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA)
             Web publishers must be aware of the needs of those getting information about NSU
             from our websites—for example, people with color blindness or other visual
             disabilities. Reasonable accommodations for them include good color contrast with
             text, labels for graphics, text descriptions for videos, and support for screen reader
             compatibility.
             Web accessibility improvements have carry-over benefits for all users. Users may
             have different browsers and different monitor resolutions. Accessibility encompasses
             the use of simple orientation tools for all users including site maps, links back to main
             pages, and large file download warnings. Everyone benefits from a well-designed,
             highly accessible web page. When developing pages, web publishers should refer to
             the http://www.section508.gov/ for guidance in creating content that is accessible to
             the widest possible audience.
61.001: Internet Website Acceptable Use and Privacy Policy                                           5

             The Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA) requires that institutions provide
             "reasonable accommodations" to clients and users with disabilities. It goes beyond
             prohibiting discrimination; it ensures inclusion for everyone in education, work-life,
             and services in their communities. NSU is committed to making all our campus
             activities accessible to users, including those who may be disabled, or differently
             abled.
Correspondence:
         Norfolk State University welcomes your feedback on the materials on our website. All
suggestions, ideas, and other information communicated to Norfolk State University through this
site shall become the exclusive property of Norfolk State University.
         You agree that none of your feedback communicated to the NSU will be obscene,
offensive, defamatory, infringing upon the intellectual property rights of others, or otherwise
objectionable or unlawful. NSU, while reserving the right to delete all or part of any
communications that it deems in its sole discretion to be objectionable, assumes no responsibility
and makes no warranty that it will undertake to do so.
Terms of Agreement
         All users of this website shall abide by all applicable federal, state, and local laws,
including those pertaining to libel, slander, defamation, trade libel, product disparagement,
harassment, invasion of privacy, and copyright and trademark infringement.
         By accessing this site, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this
agreement. This agreement shall be governed by the common law of Virginia relating to written
agreements without giving effect to any conflict of laws principles, as well as other statutory
provisions, and shall be interpreted and enforced. All activity occurring in connection with the
site (including, but not limited to, accessing pages, and downloading materials) is presumed to
occur in the State of Virginia.
Customer comments or review
         If you have questions about this privacy statement or the practices of this website, or if
you choose to review or correct any information you previously submitted, please contact us at
mailto:webmaster@nsu.edu.
61.001: Internet Website Acceptable Use and Privacy Policy                                        6
